<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Grafana Blog</title>
  <subtitle>Blog posts on Grafana, Metrics, Graphite, Monitoring, Build measure learn</subtitle>
  <id>http://grafana.org/blog</id>
  <link href="http://grafana.org/blog"/>
  <link href="http://grafana.org/feed.xml" rel="self"/>
  <updated>2015-04-09T00:00:00Z</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Grafana</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <title>March 2015 User Survey</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://grafana.org/blog/2015/04/09/March15-Survery.html"/>
    <id>http://grafana.org/blog/2015/04/09/March15-Survery.html</id>
    <published>2015-04-09T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2015-04-09T17:22:52+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Torkel Ödegaard</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/assets/img/blog/grafana_survey_results800.png" class="no-shadow"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On March 1st 2015, we asked the Grafana community for a favor. We published a public
survey to solicit feedback on the current state of the product to better understand how
Grafana is being used and to weigh in on some new features we were considering.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The number and the quality of responses exceeded our expectations. Lots of really useful
feedback on what is missing and what could be better. There were also a lot of
gratifying compliments about how much everyone appreciate Grafana.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://infogr.am/grafana_user_survey_mar2015"&gt;Check out the survey results&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Grafana 2.0-Beta1 Released</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://grafana.org/blog/2015/03/30/Grafana-2-Beta1.html"/>
    <id>http://grafana.org/blog/2015/03/30/Grafana-2-Beta1.html</id>
    <published>2015-03-30T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2015-03-30T18:52:57+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Torkel Ödegaard</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Today is an exciting day for the Grafana project, Grafana 2.0-beta1 is released! So much hard work
during the last 5 months has gone in to making this release.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Grafana 2.0 comes with its own backend server (written in Go). So upgrading requires a little
more than for previous upgrades. Dashboards are 100% backward compatible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We provide &lt;code class="prettyprint"&gt;deb&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code class="prettyprint"&gt;rpm&lt;/code&gt; and regular binary tar packages for download. If your platform is not included, check the &lt;a href="http://docs.grafana.org/v2.0/project/building_from_source/"&gt;Building from source&lt;/a&gt;
guide.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://grafana.org/download"&gt;Download&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://docs.grafana.org/v2.0/installation/"&gt;Installation guide&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://docs.grafana.org/v2.0/installation/migrating_to2/"&gt;Migrating from 1.x to 2.x&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id="what&amp;#39;s-new-in-grafana-v2.0"&gt;What&amp;rsquo;s New in Grafana v2.0&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are so many new features (as well as fixes) to talk about. Below is some of the highlights.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="dashboard-snapshot-sharing"&gt;Dashboard Snapshot sharing&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A dashboard snapshot is an instant way to share an interactive dashboard publicly. When created, we &lt;strong&gt;strip sensitive data&lt;/strong&gt; like queries
(metric, template and annotation) and panel links, leaving only the visible metric data and series names embedded into your dashboard. Dashboard
snapshots can be accessed by anyone who has the link and can reach the URL.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://docs.grafana.org/img/v2/dashboard_snapshot_dialog.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id="publish-snapshots"&gt;Publish snapshots&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can publish snapshots to you local instance or to &lt;a href="http://snapshot.raintank.io"&gt;snapshot.raintank.io&lt;/a&gt;. The later is a free service
that is provided by &lt;a href="http://raintank.io"&gt;Raintank&lt;/a&gt; that allows you to publish dashboard snapshots to an external grafana instance.
The same rules still apply, anyone with the link can view it. You can set an expiration time if you want the snapshot to be removed
after a certain time period.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dashboard snapshots are really useful when you want to share a whole dashboard or just a panel with an external client who do not
have access to your Grafana instance. Instead of taking a picture you can snapshot the current visible data
and share an interactive dashboard. It can also be used in combination with panel iframe embedding (mentioned below).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="panel-time-overrides-&amp;amp;-timeshift"&gt;Panel time overrides &amp;amp; timeshift&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In Grafana v2.x you can now override the relative time range for individual panels. You can also add a
time shift to individual panels. This allows you to show metrics from different time periods or days
at the same time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://docs.grafana.org/img/v2/panel_time_override.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You control these overrides in panel editor mode and the new tab &lt;code class="prettyprint"&gt;Time Range&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://docs.grafana.org/img/v2/time_range_tab.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Currently you can only override the dashboard time with relative time ranges, not absolute time ranges. When
you zoom or change the dashboard time to a custom absolute time range the panel overrides will be disabled. The
panel relative time override is only active when the dashboard time is also relative. The panel timeshift override
however is always active, even when the dashboard time is absolute.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;code class="prettyprint"&gt;Hide time override info&lt;/code&gt; option allows you to hide the the override info text that is by default shown in the
upper right of a panel when overriden time range options.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="panel-iframe-embedding"&gt;Panel IFrame embedding&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can embed a single panel on another web page using the panel share dialog. Below you should see an iframe
with a graph panel (taken from dashoard snapshot at &lt;a href="http://snapshot.raintank.io"&gt;snapshot.raintank.io&lt;/a&gt;. Try
hovering or zooming on the panel below!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe src="http://snapshot.raintank.io/dashboard/solo/snapshot/IQ7iZF00sHalq0Ffjv6OyclJSA1YHYV1?panelId=4&amp;fullscreen" width="650" height="300" frameborder="0"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;h3 id="new-dashboard-top-header"&gt;New dashboard top header&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="no-shadow" src="http://docs.grafana.org/img/v2/v2_top_nav_annotated.png"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Side menu toggle&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dashboard title &amp;amp; Search dropdown (also includes access to New dashboard, Import &amp;amp; Playlist)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Star/unstar current dashboard&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Share current dashboard (Make sure the dashboard is saved before)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Save current dashboard&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Settings dropdown (dashboard settings, annotations, templating, etc)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note&lt;/strong&gt; In Grafana v2.0 when you change the title of a dashboard and then save it it will no
longer create a new dashboard. It will just change the name for the current dashboard.
To change name and create a new dashboard use the &lt;code class="prettyprint"&gt;Save As...&lt;/code&gt; menu option&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id="new-search-view-&amp;amp;-starring-dashboards"&gt;New search view &amp;amp; starring dashboards&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://docs.grafana.org/img/v2/dashboard_search.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The dashboard search view has received a big UI update and polish. You can now see and filter by which dashboard
you have personally starred.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="logarithmic-scale"&gt;Logarithmic scale&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Graph panel now supports 3 logarithmic scales, &lt;code class="prettyprint"&gt;log base 10&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code class="prettyprint"&gt;log base 32&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code class="prettyprint"&gt;log base 1024&lt;/code&gt;. Logarithmic y-axis
scales are very useful when rendering many series of different order of magnitude on the same scale. For example
latency, network traffic or storage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://docs.grafana.org/img/v2/graph_logbase10_ms.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="dashbord-list-panel"&gt;Dashbord list panel&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://docs.grafana.org/img/v2/dashlist_starred.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is one new panel in Grafana v2.0 and that is the &lt;code class="prettyprint"&gt;Dashboard list&lt;/code&gt; panel. This panel can show the current
signed in user&amp;rsquo;s starred dashboards or dashboards based on a custom search (keyword or tags).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="data-source-proxy-&amp;amp;-admin-views"&gt;Data Source proxy &amp;amp; admin views&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Data sources in Grafana v2.0 are NOT defined in a config file but added through the UI. The backend can also
handle proxying data source metric requests which means that it is a lot easier to get started using Grafana with
Graphite or OpenTSDB without having to spend time with nginx CORS (Cross origin resource sharing) work arounds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note&lt;/strong&gt; For InfluxDB users: The data source proxy feature will
hide database user &amp;amp; password details from the frontend / browser.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id="relative-time-now-delay"&gt;Relative time now delay&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A problem that has plagued many is the fact that graphs tend to dip to zero by the end because metrics for
the last interval has yet to be received by the time series database. You can now work around this by adding
a now delay in &lt;code class="prettyprint"&gt;Dashboard Settings&lt;/code&gt; &amp;gt; &lt;code class="prettyprint"&gt;Time Picker&lt;/code&gt; tab.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://docs.grafana.org/img/v2/timepicker_now_delay.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="overwrite-protection"&gt;Overwrite protection&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Grafana v2.0 will protect you and your other Grafana users from accidentally overwriting each others changes
to the same dashboard. The same protection also applies if you try to create a new dashboard with a
name that already exists.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://docs.grafana.org/img/v2/overwrite_protection.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="user-preferences"&gt;User preferences&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you open side menu (by clicking on the Grafana icon in the top header) you can access your profile page.
Here you can update your user details, UI Theme and change password.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="png-rendering"&gt;PNG rendering&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the panel share dialog you now have access to a link that will render the panel to a PNG image.
The panel is rendered on the backend via phantomjs (headless browser). This requires that your metric
data source is accessible from your Grafana server host machine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://docs.grafana.org/img/v2/share_dialog_image_highlight.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="user-&amp;amp;-organization-permissions"&gt;User &amp;amp; Organization permissions&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All dashboards and data sources are linked to an organization (not to a user). Users are linked to
Organizations via a role. That role can be:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code class="prettyprint"&gt;Viewer&lt;/code&gt;: Can only view dashboards, not save / create them.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code class="prettyprint"&gt;Editor&lt;/code&gt;: Can view, update and create dashboards.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code class="prettyprint"&gt;Admin&lt;/code&gt;: Everything an Editor can plus edit and add data sources and organization users.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note&lt;/strong&gt; A &lt;code class="prettyprint"&gt;Viewer&lt;/code&gt; can still view all metrics exposed through a data source, not only
the metrics used in already existing dashboards. That is because there are not
per series permissions in Graphite, InfluxDB or OpenTSDB.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are currently no permissions on individual dashboards.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="documentation"&gt;Documentation&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The documentation site has been updated. You can still access v1.9 docs via the version selector. The documentation
now live in the &lt;a href="https://github.com/grafana/grafana/tree/master/docs"&gt;main grafana repository&lt;/a&gt;. If you spot a mistake in
the docs or want to improve it, do not hesitate to submit a PR.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The documentation has partly been updated for 2.0, we will continuing to work on docs in the coming days and weeks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="feedback-and-bug-reports"&gt;Feedback and bug reports&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please report any issues you have on &lt;a href="https://github.com/grafana/grafana/issues"&gt;github&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="thanks-to-project-sponsors"&gt;Thanks to project sponsors&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.squarespace.com"&gt;Squarespace&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.dreamhost.com"&gt;Dreamhost&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.demonware.net"&gt;Demonware&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://developer.mediamath.com/OpenSource"&gt;Mediamath&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;section class="newsletter"&gt;
  &lt;form action="http://grafana.us8.list-manage.com/subscribe/post?u=2aeb5711db2aececc990be536&amp;amp;id=5585d37ecc" method="post" id="mc-embedded-subscribe-form" name="mc-embedded-subscribe-form" class="validate" target="_blank"&gt;
    &lt;row class="collapse"&gt;
      &lt;div class="medium-10 columns"&gt;
        &lt;input type="email" value="" name="EMAIL" class="email" id="mce-EMAIL" placeholder="email address"&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;div class="medium-2 columns"&gt;
        &lt;input type="submit" value="Subscribe" name="subscribe" id="mc-embedded-subscribe" class="button postfix"&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/row&gt;
  &lt;/form&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Grafana 2.0 Alpha &amp; Preview</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://grafana.org/blog/2015/02/10/Grafana-2-Alpha-and-preview.html"/>
    <id>http://grafana.org/blog/2015/02/10/Grafana-2-Alpha-and-preview.html</id>
    <published>2015-02-10T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2015-03-05T15:21:55+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Torkel Ödegaard</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;As some of you already know, at least those who read the previous blog post &lt;a href="http://grafana.org/blog/2015/01/12/grafana2-the-future-and-raintank.html"&gt;on the future of Grafana&lt;/a&gt;,
we have been working on a backend for the Grafana 2.0 release. A backend is really essential if Grafana is to be able
to expand its capabilities to support alerting, PNG rendering of panels, and of course user managment and authentication.
A backend will also make it easier to install and get started with Grafana as you will no longer need to learn how to
configure nginx or deal with complex CORS issues for Graphite or OpenTSDB. Something that
many new users struggle with when setting up Grafana for the first time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Grafana 2.0 has been long in the making but has seen accelerated progress in the last two months
thanks to my collegues at &lt;a href="http://raintank.io"&gt;Raintank&lt;/a&gt;, where we are working on building a nextgen open source
infrastructure monitoring platform.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/assets/img/blog/Grafana2_Preview_1.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="code-&amp;amp;-docker-image"&gt;Code &amp;amp; Docker image&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Grafana 2.0 backend and frontend changes are now public in the &lt;a href="https://github.com/grafana/grafana/tree/develop"&gt;develop&lt;/a&gt;
branch in the main grafana repository on Github. The readme on that branch contains instructions for how to build and run the
new backend. You can also try it using docker with a single line like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="highlight text"&gt;docker run -i -p 3000:3000 grafana/grafana:develop
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are no offical binary packages yet as there is still some work that needs
to be done before a beta release can be made. Grafana 2.0 is not ready for
production use yet. If you want to help please checkout out the develop branch
or try the docker image and submit feedback and bug reports on github!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is no updated documentation for Grafana 2.0, that is one of the items we will work on
in the run up to a beta release.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can also try out a preview build on &lt;a href="http://play.grafana.org/v2"&gt;play.grafana.org/v2&lt;/a&gt;, login with
guest/guest or you can signup. If you signup you will be automatically added as a Viewer to the main account.
This preview is automatically updated after each successful commit &amp;amp; build of the develop branch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="the-backend"&gt;The backend&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The backend is written in Go and defaults to an embedded sqlite3 database so there is no dependency on
Elasticsearch for dashboards storage. If you are already using InfluxDB or Elasticsearch for dashboard
storage there is an import feature under the account page where you can import your existing dashboards.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="panel-rendering"&gt;Panel rendering&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The backend supports rendering any panel to a PNG image, this will enable some slick integration
in the future with services like Slack and Hipchat. When we eventually tackle alerting this feature
should also come in handy as we could provide images of related graphs along with alert notifications.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Currently the PNG rendering feature is a just a simple link in the share panel dialog.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="user-&amp;amp;-account-model"&gt;User &amp;amp; Account model&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To support SaaS and larger Grafana installations we have added a User and Account model similar to
how Google Analytics has implemented this. Dashboards, data sources, etc are not tied to a specific user
but to an Account, users are linked to accounts with a specific Role (Admin, Editor, Viewer).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To simplify smaller Grafana setups you can configure Grafana to be in a single account mode where new user
signups are automatically assigned to a specific account. And you can also enable anonymous access if you
do not care about authentication or user managment at all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Currently users can signup and login with a specified email/password or via Github or Google OAuth integration.
LDAP integration is in on the roadmap but not implemented yet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="ui-changes"&gt;UI Changes&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was a big challange to modify the existing Grafana UI to accomodate more views like Profile, Account,
Datasources, Admin etc, without sacrificing the clean simple top navigation. We tried many alternatives
of sidebars and collapsable top top navbars.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/assets/img/animated_gifs/grafana2_sidenav_gif1.gif" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The above animated gif shows the sidebar we ended up with, as well as the new dashboard search dropdown.
We will continue to refine and polish this solution. For more on the creative process and details
on all the UI mockups and navigation alternatives we explored read this
&lt;a href="https://blog.raintank.io/ux-the-long-road-to-the-shortest-path"&gt;blog post by Matt Toback&lt;/a&gt;. Matt is lead
on customer experiance at &lt;a href="http://raintank.io"&gt;Raintank&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="dashboard-list-panel"&gt;Dashboard list panel&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is currently one new panel in Grafana 2.0 that can show the current user&amp;rsquo;s starred dashboards as well
as a list of dashboards based on search query or dashboard tags.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/assets/img/blog/dashlist_panel_1.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is a &lt;a href="https://github.com/grafana/grafana/issues/1449"&gt;github issue&lt;/a&gt; for this new panel where feedback
would be greatly appreciated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="standalone-mode"&gt;Standalone mode&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The frontend has been slighly changed to support a standalone mode where it can work mostly like Grafana has
in the past, that is without any backend. This mode is currently broken in the develop branch but will
be made functioning again before release. We belive that many Grafana users value the pure frontend (no backend)
nature of Grafana and we would hate to abandon or dissapoint this user group so we will try to support
a standalone mode and build as long as the interest is high and the complexity of supporting both is acceptable.
But it is likely that long term this standalone mode will be removed, but this is all up to user feedback.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="beta"&gt;Beta&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So stay tuned for a beta sometime early or mid March (if this goes as we hope).
Subscribe to newsletter to get notified.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;section class="newsletter"&gt;
  &lt;form action="http://grafana.us8.list-manage.com/subscribe/post?u=2aeb5711db2aececc990be536&amp;amp;id=5585d37ecc" method="post" id="mc-embedded-subscribe-form" name="mc-embedded-subscribe-form" class="validate" target="_blank"&gt;
    &lt;row class="collapse"&gt;
      &lt;div class="medium-10 columns"&gt;
        &lt;input type="email" value="" name="EMAIL" class="email" id="mce-EMAIL" placeholder="email address"&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;div class="medium-2 columns"&gt;
        &lt;input type="submit" value="Subscribe" name="subscribe" id="mc-embedded-subscribe" class="button postfix"&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/row&gt;
  &lt;/form&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="thanks-to-project-sponsors"&gt;Thanks to project sponsors&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.squarespace.com"&gt;Squarespace&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.dreamhost.com"&gt;Dreamhost&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.demonware.net"&gt;Demonware&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://developer.mediamath.com/OpenSource"&gt;Mediamath&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Grafana 2.0, the future, and raintank</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://grafana.org/blog/2015/01/12/grafana2-the-future-and-raintank.html"/>
    <id>http://grafana.org/blog/2015/01/12/grafana2-the-future-and-raintank.html</id>
    <published>2015-01-12T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2015-01-13T10:13:10+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Torkel Ödegaard</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;This is a semi long blog post about my experience working on Grafana during 2014 and the plans for 2015.
So if you want to skip the personal &amp;amp; history stuff jump to the end for some news and plans for 2015.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="in-the-beginning"&gt;In the beginning&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Grafana has now been in development for a little over one year. The first commit dates to Dec 5 2013.
It started just as a late night hack trying to get Graphite to work with the histogram panel in Kibana.
I had just started using Kibana at work and fell instantly in love with it. It was just so awesome at
analyzing logs and its beautiful dark UI made it easy to build dashboards without having to manually
edit json files. Something that many alternative Graphite dashboards required.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My late night Kibana + Graphite hack worked so well that I quickly started imagining my dream Graphite
dashboard and graph composer and spent almost all of Christmas 2013 working non stop on realizing those
initial ideas. Ideas like a full screen graph edit mode and an intelligent Graphite expression builder
that makes graphite expressions more readable, editable and understandable. Of all the features in Grafana,
I am most proud of the Graphite expression and function editor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div &gt;
  &lt;img src="/assets/img/blog/graphite_query_editor.png"/&gt;
  &lt;h4&gt;
  &lt;small&gt;&lt;em&gt;The graphite query editor, showing the same query in text
    edit mode and in the Grafana graphite editor mode
    &lt;/em&gt;
  &lt;/small&gt;
  &lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I did not really expect much when I first released Grafana 1.0 on January 19th. There was such a plethora of
other Graphite dashboards, so who would care about yet another one? Boy was I wrong. The reaction was really
amazing. That evening after the first release Grafana went “mini” viral within the Graphite community and
my phone buzzed constantly for about 40 minutes from all the retweets!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All the positive reaction gave me a lot energy and the will to spend most of my free time on Grafana during
winter and spring 2014. I used to come to work at 7am to be able to squeeze in an hour on Grafana before
having to start doing “real work”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="monitorama-may-2014"&gt;Monitorama May 2014&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jason Dixon (@obfuscurity), one of the main developers on the Graphite project, invited me to speak at
the Monitorma conference in Portland (a GREAT monitoring conference that is organized by Jason).
I got a chance to meet and talk to some great people, like Jason, Luke Kanies, Paul Dix from InfluxDB,
Dave Concannon from Hosted Graphite, and many others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The reaction to my talk and from the many attendees that came up to me to express their love and thanks
for Grafana was really amazing. There is going to be another Monitorama in June 2015, see you there!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="full-time-work"&gt;Full time work&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By the end of April I was itching to work on Grafana full time. There were so many potential
improvements and so little time. So I decided to quit my contracting work after the summer and start
working on Grafana full time. I had some savings in my company that would last me about a year so I figured
that it could be fun year working on open source. I also planned to explore options to commercialize
Grafana or seek sponsorships. Summer went and so did autumn. I had a blast working on Grafana full time,
releasing some pretty big improvements in v1.7 and v1.8. User adoption kept on growing, as did user feedback
and contributions. I also managed to get some sponsors!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="contributions-and-sponsorships"&gt;Contributions and Sponsorships&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A special thanks to all who have contributed to Gafana during last year in terms of pull request contributions,
feedback on github and IRC. A special thanks goes to Grafana’s sponsors: &lt;a href="http://www.squarespace.com"&gt;Squarespace&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.dreamhost.com/"&gt;Dreamhost&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://www.demonware.net/"&gt;Demonware&lt;/a&gt;
for helping support full the time work on Grafana.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="grafana-in-2015"&gt;Grafana in 2015&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I started working on Grafana full time I also started working on a Grafana backend.
I figured that a Grafana backend that could do authentication, server side rendering of panels,
integration with hipchat &amp;amp; slack, alerting etc could be a “Pro” version that I could charge money for.
I did not spend much time on this backend as there was so much I wanted to get done in the frontend
so it never saw the light of day in 2014.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="raintank"&gt;Raintank&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are no longer any plans for a closed source or commercial version of Grafana. The backend powered version
will be 100% open source. What is making this possible is Grafana’s sponsors and a company I am co-founding
together with Raj Dutt (founder of Voxel) and Anthony Woods. The company is called &lt;a href="http://raintank.io"&gt;Raintank&lt;/a&gt; and
will focus on building and providing a SaaS platform around open source metric and monitoring solutions
(Grafana is one among them). This SaaS platform will be completely open source.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We have assembled a great team with a lot of engineering and design talent that will, among many other things,
accelerate Gafana development and strengthen the open source monitoring community.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="grafana-2.0"&gt;Grafana 2.0&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So the good news is that there will NOT be any splintering of the Grafana user community into Pro/Enterprise
users and OSS users. There will just be one open source Grafana codebase and variant. There will continue to
be a standalone build for users who prefer the pure frontend nature of Grafana. The Grafana frontend architecture
has been slighly redesigned to work in both standalone and backend mode. In backend mode it will utilize the backend
for saving and searching dashboards, as well as a number of views that will be enabled (login, admin, etc).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The features that the backend will enable in Grafana 2.0 will initially be:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Integrated dashboard &amp;amp; user database (sqlite3)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Can also use mysql or postgres as database&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Multi-tenant user accounts and authorization (can be disabled)

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;User &amp;amp; password&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Github OAuth&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Google OAuth&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;LDAP integration&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Server side rendering of panels to PNG images&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Easy admin UI for data sources (can also be configured via config file)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Integrated data source http proxy for all datasources (to work around CORS issues)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;HTTP API&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Migration script for dashboards stored in Elasticsearch or InfluxDB&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is the very basic set that we are aiming for right now. There will probably be a lot of enhancements in the
existing dashboard and panel features and the initial release will be quickly followed by more advanced features
like integration with hipchat, slack &amp;amp; hubot, user preferences and eventually alerting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Grafana 2.0 is currently not ready for a alpha or beta. But the code and a preview version will
be made public shorty, hopefully within 2-3 weeks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id="other-news"&gt;Other news&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Grafana 1.9.1 was released two weeks ago (in case you missed this)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Grafana now has a user and developer mailing list. &lt;a href="https://groups.io/org/groupsio/grafana"&gt;Subscribe here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Graphite 0.9.13-pre1 has been released! &lt;a href="http://graphite.readthedocs.org/en/latest/releases/0_9_13.html"&gt;Read the release notes&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The &lt;a href="https://github.com/grafana/grafana-plugins"&gt;Grafana plugins&lt;/a&gt; repository has seen some activity lately with updates for the KairosDB datasource and a basic implementation
for an Atlas datasource (the Netflix metrics db).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Grafana 1.9.0-rc1 Released!</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://grafana.org/blog/2014/11/17/grafana-1-9-0-rc1-released.html"/>
    <id>http://grafana.org/blog/2014/11/17/grafana-1-9-0-rc1-released.html</id>
    <published>2014-11-17T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2014-11-17T16:29:17+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Torkel Ödegaard</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;New release today! v1.9.0-rc1 is now available for &lt;a href="/download"&gt;download&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://play.grafana.org"&gt;play.grafana.org&lt;/a&gt; is updated to run 1.9.0-rc1.
There is also a &lt;a href="http://play.grafana.org/#/dashboard/db/new-features-in-v19"&gt;New features in v1.9&lt;/a&gt;
dashboard that highlights some of the new features.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No breaking changes, so update should be problem free. But this is a release candidate so
there could be some bugs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="release-highlights"&gt;Release highlights&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h4 id="1)-singlestat-panel"&gt;1) Singlestat panel&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This release marks the introduction of a new panel!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/assets/img/docs/singlestat_panel_1.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A multitude of options makes this panel pretty flexible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add sparkline to the bottom of the panel&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add text before/after the value&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add color thresholds for the value or the panel background&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Control font size&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Adding a panel link makes the whole panel act as a link to another dashboard&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id="2)-share-panel-feature"&gt;2) Share panel feature&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Click on panel title area (anywhere works, does not need to be the title text) to open the
new panel menu. Click on the &lt;code class="prettyprint"&gt;share&lt;/code&gt; button to open the new share dialog. In this dialog
you get a URL to that panel with the current time range and any template variables
embedded in the URL.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/assets/img/blog/panel_menu.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id="3)-fill-below-to"&gt;3) Fill below to&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An new series specific style has been added in this release that is very
useful when visualizing max/min as shadow behind an average.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/assets/img/docs/fillbelow_to.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This display style is specified by adding a series override rule for the series
above (ex. max). The value of the option is the series name to fill to (ex min).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Example:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/assets/img/blog/fillbelow_to_option.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id="4)-other-graph-features-&amp;amp;-enhancements"&gt;4) Other graph features &amp;amp; enhancements&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Shared tooltip option, shows every series when hovering&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Toggle legend from panel menu&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Improved legend table mode look&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sort legend series (only works in table mode)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Multi graph crosshair line (shows a vertical red line where you hover on all graphs)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/assets/img/animated_gifs/legend_features.gif" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id="5)-panel-links"&gt;5) Panel links&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the General tab you can now add links to other dashboards or absolute links
to other web apps. These links can then be accessed from the panel menu. Links
to other dashboards will preserve the current time range.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/assets/img/docs/drilldown_links.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You access these links from the panel menu dropdown. The whole singlestat panel
will act as link if a drilldown / detail link is added to the panel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="metrics-meetup-in-san-francisco,-december-3rd"&gt;Metrics meetup in San Francisco, December 3rd&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I will be flying to San Francisco on November 28th and will stay for one week.
Rackspace will be hosting a metrics meetup on December 3rd at their office on 620
Folsom St. I will be speaking about Grafana (showing new and upcoming stuff) and Rackspace will be speaking about
there open source time series system &lt;a href="http://blueflood.io/"&gt;Blueflood&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.meetup.com/San-Francisco-Metrics-Meetup/events/218611974/"&gt;Sign up for the meetup&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="meetups,-conferences-&amp;amp;-company-talks/coaching"&gt;Meetups, Conferences &amp;amp; Company talks/coaching&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want me to come and talk about Grafana, application metrics, build measure learn or Graphite.
Please email me at &lt;a href="mailto:contact@grafana.org"&gt;torkel@grafana.org&lt;/a&gt;. I live in Stockholm Sweden so
travel could be an issue, but I am flexible and available :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cheers &amp;amp; keep on graphing!&lt;br&gt;
Torkel&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Big thanks to my sponsors&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.squarespace.com"&gt;Sponsored by Squarespace&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.dreamhost.com"&gt;Sponsored by Dreamhost&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Grafana 1.8.0-rc1 Released!</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://grafana.org/blog/2014/09/11/grafana-1-8-0-rc1-released.html"/>
    <id>http://grafana.org/blog/2014/09/11/grafana-1-8-0-rc1-released.html</id>
    <published>2014-09-11T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2014-09-12T16:24:17+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Torkel Ödegaard</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;New release today! v1.8.0-rc1 is now available for &lt;a href="/download"&gt;download&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is probably the biggest release since the first version was released. So many new features, enhancements and general UI improvements
that this will likely be a very long blog post. &lt;a href="http://play.grafana.org"&gt;play.grafana.org&lt;/a&gt; is updated to
run 1.8.0-rc1, now with InfluxDB demo dashboards. There is also a &lt;a href="http://play.grafana.org/#/dashboard/db/new-features-in-v18"&gt;New features in v1.8&lt;/a&gt;
dashboard that highlights some of the new features.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="release-highlights"&gt;Release highlights&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h4 id="1)-mixed-graph-styling"&gt;1) Mixed graph styling&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can override any display setting for a specific series using the series name or a regex pattern. Mix bars with lines, or disable
stacking for the right y-axis or any combination you can think of!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/assets/img/blog/mixed_styles.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You find these options under display styles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/assets/img/blog/series_override_options.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id="2)-improved-templating-system"&gt;2) Improved templating system&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The templating system has been completly rewritten. This feature was previously called filtering. From 1.8 it is renamed to templating.
Templating allows you to create variables that you can use in metric queries, annotation queries and panel titles to create generic reusable
dashboards. The new templating system uses a &lt;code class="prettyprint"&gt;$variable&lt;/code&gt; syntax, but the old &lt;code class="prettyprint"&gt;[[variable]]&lt;/code&gt; still works.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;New templating editor&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/assets/img/blog/template_variable_list.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The new templating system now has full support for InfluxDB. You can extract parts of a metric name using a regex.
You also have full control over how the &amp;ldquo;All&amp;rdquo; option should be formated so that it works for different
data sources.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/assets/img/blog/template_editor_influxdb.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;InfluxDB users should use &lt;code class="prettyprint"&gt;regex wildcard&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code class="prettyprint"&gt;regex values&lt;/code&gt; for the &lt;code class="prettyprint"&gt;All&lt;/code&gt; option format.
Graphite users should use &lt;code class="prettyprint"&gt;glob&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code class="prettyprint"&gt;wildcard&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Variables in Graphite function parameters&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
You can now use template variables for function parameters. There is a special template variable type called &lt;code class="prettyprint"&gt;interval&lt;/code&gt; that includes
and auto value, where the interval is calculated based on the time range.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/assets/img/blog/graphite_func_variables.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/assets/img/docs/template_variable_interval.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Template variable selection&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
When selecting template variables you now get a text box and and auto complete dropdown. Useful when you have many posible values for
a variable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id="3)-ui-improvements"&gt;3) UI Improvements&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;No more modals&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
All editors are now shown in an edit pane under the menu. This feels much more natural and faster.
All editors have also been polished and generally look a little better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/assets/img/blog/new_editor_look.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Improved search &amp;amp; tags&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
The search results view has been given a makeover, now with colored tags.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/assets/img/blog/new_search_look.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can navigate the search results with your up/down keys. The first
result is always highlighted. Hit enter to open the dashboard. You can add tags in the dashboard
settings edit pane. You can hit the tab key, to focus the tags link, hit enter again to get
an overview of all tags, click on the tag to filter by the tag.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id="4)-improved-graphite-query-editor"&gt;4) Improved Graphite Query editor&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many graphite functions can take other series as arguments. This was something the old
query editor could not handle. But the new improved query editor allows you to use
other queries as function arguments. To refer to another query you use a letter, like &lt;code class="prettyprint"&gt;#A&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/assets/img/blog/graphite_complex_query1.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Or a shorter version of the same thing:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/assets/img/blog/graphite_complex_query2.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is very powerful as it allows you to reuse queries in complex expressions. For example
plot a total and a percentage. If a query is only to be used in another query and not drawn
simply hide it using the eye.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id="5)-influxdb-query-editor-enhancements"&gt;5) InfluxDB Query Editor enhancements&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The query editor for InfluxDB has been upgraded. There are now two rows for each query, so more space
for potentially long series names. There is now an option to add &lt;code class="prettyprint"&gt;fill(null)&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code class="prettyprint"&gt;fill(0)&lt;/code&gt;. These options
are very important to understand and use because they solve some important scenarios that has troubled many
InfluxDB users.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/assets/img/blog/influxdb_new_query_editor.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A setting that is very important in combination with &lt;code class="prettyprint"&gt;fill(0)&lt;/code&gt; is the new group by time option below your
queries. This option allows you to set a fixed group by time for all queries, but more importantly it allows
you to set a lower limit for the auto group by time. When using &lt;code class="prettyprint"&gt;fill(0)&lt;/code&gt; you do not want to insert
zeros between real measurements, so you group by time must never be below the rate of writes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A low limit for the auto group by time is set using &lt;code class="prettyprint"&gt;&amp;gt;10s&lt;/code&gt; syntax. This feature together with &lt;code class="prettyprint"&gt;fill(0)&lt;/code&gt; is important when stacking multiple
series to ensure that every series have values for every time point.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id="6)-influxdb-breaking-changes"&gt;6) InfluxDB breaking changes&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am sorry to say that there are some breaking changes in 1.8 for InfluxDB users. All queries that used
a where clause or raw queries needs to be updated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Raw Queries&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="highlight sql"&gt;&lt;span class="k"&gt;select&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;mean&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;value&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="k"&gt;from&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="nv"&gt;&amp;quot;app.status&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="k"&gt;where&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="err"&gt;$&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;timeFilter&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="k"&gt;group&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="k"&gt;by&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;time&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="err"&gt;$&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;interval&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;fill&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="mi"&gt;0&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="k"&gt;order&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="k"&gt;asc&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Raw queries are now required to include &lt;code class="prettyprint"&gt;$timeFilter&lt;/code&gt; variable for time range, and zoom to work. Before
Grafana tried to parse and inject the time range filter in the right place, but this was fragile and could
lead to double time where conditions if there already was one in the query. Raw queries can now use,
optionally, a &lt;code class="prettyprint"&gt;$interval&lt;/code&gt; variable which will be replaced with the auto group by time interval.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Where condition&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 1.7.0 you could add a single where condition, using a dropdown to select column, operation, and value.
This was overly complicated, and is now replaced with a single where condition text box where you
can enter any number of where conditions. If you open a graph in edit mode the editor will try to
patch the query (using the old model) to build the where condition for you. But you will have to
enter edit mode for this &amp;ldquo;patch&amp;rdquo; process to work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id="6)-misc-improvements"&gt;6) Misc improvements&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Url state for panel edit and fullscreen mode, copy url and you will be taken to edit or fullscreen for that panel&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;from and to date range filters can be passed via url, see &lt;a href="https://github.com/grafana/grafana/issues/787"&gt;Issue #787&lt;/a&gt;
for more details&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A full share feature, where you can share a panel or dashboard with the current time range did not
make it for this release. But will be coming.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id="7)-documentation"&gt;7) Documentation&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The documentation for the new features and changes has yet to be done. That will be the focus for next
week. In the mean time, this blog post and the demo dashboards on &lt;a href="http://play.grafana.org"&gt;play.grafana.org&lt;/a&gt;
will have to suffice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id="8)-download"&gt;8) Download&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even though I have two project sponsors, it is not enough
for me to work full time and long term on Grafana. So please &lt;a href="/donate"&gt;pay what you think it is worth&lt;/a&gt;, and head to the &lt;a href="/download"&gt;download&lt;/a&gt; page
for download links and a complete changelog.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="nyc-grafana-+-influxdb-meetup-on-oct-8th"&gt;NYC Grafana + InfluxDB Meetup on Oct 8th&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I will be flying to New York on Oct 5th and will stay for two weeks. My project sponsor
&lt;a href="http://www.squarespace.com/"&gt;Squarespace&lt;/a&gt; will be hosting a meetup on Oct 8th where I
and Paul Dix from InfluxDB will be speaking. &lt;a href="http://www.meetup.com/Monitoring-NYC/events/205947512/"&gt;Sign up&lt;/a&gt;
for the meetup!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="meetups,-conferences-&amp;amp;-company-talks/coaching"&gt;Meetups, Conferences &amp;amp; Company talks/coaching&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want me to come talk about Grafana, application metrics, build measure learn or Graphite.
Please email me at &lt;a href="mailto:contact@grafana.org"&gt;torkel@grafana.org&lt;/a&gt;. I live in Stockholm Sweden so
travel could be an issue, but I am flexible and available :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cheers &amp;amp; keep on graphing!&lt;br&gt;
Torkel&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Big thanks to my sponsors&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.squarespace.com"&gt;Sponsored by Squarespace&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.dreamhost.com"&gt;Sponsored by Dreamhost&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
</feed>
