<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Grafana Blog</title>
  <subtitle>Blog posts on Grafana, Metrics, Graphite, Monitoring, Build measure learn</subtitle>
  <id>http://grafana.org/blog</id>
  <link href="http://grafana.org/blog"/>
  <link href="http://grafana.org/feed.xml" rel="self"/>
  <updated>2014-08-05T00:00:00Z</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Grafana</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <title>Grafana 1.7.0-rc1 Released!</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://grafana.org/blog/2014/08/05/grafana-1-7-0-rc1-released.html"/>
    <id>http://grafana.org/blog/2014/08/05/grafana-1-7-0-rc1-released.html</id>
    <published>2014-08-05T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2014-08-05T15:09:24+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Torkel Ödegaard</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;New release today! v1.7.0-rc1 is now available for &lt;a href="/download"&gt;download&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a big release with a many new features and improvements. There are also a large number
of architectural changes (hence the release candidate status).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="release-highlights"&gt;Release highlights&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;InfluxDB can now be used as dashboard storage&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;InfluxDB can be used as a data source for annotations&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;InfluxDB series aliasing improvements (alias patterns)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Elasticsearch can be used as an annotation data source&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;New &lt;strong&gt;graph legend&lt;/strong&gt; options: &lt;em&gt;Align as table&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Right side&lt;/em&gt;.
Align as table will list series in vertical column, legend values will also align. Right side will place
the legend to the right side of the graph.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/assets/img/docs/graph_legend_right_table.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="documentation"&gt;Documentation&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The documentation has also seen an overhaul with many improvements and additions. A new &lt;a href="/docs/features/intro"&gt;Getting started&lt;/a&gt; guide
and a new &lt;a href="/docs/troubleshooting"&gt;Troubleshooting&lt;/a&gt; guide for example.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="fixes-and-small-additions"&gt;Fixes and small additions&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are a number of more small improvements and fixes in this release. It also has a number of architectural improvements
that will make future features and additions easier to implement and manage. Check the changelog on the &lt;a href="/download"&gt;download page&lt;/a&gt;
for a complete list.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="grafana-&amp;amp;-full-time-development"&gt;Grafana &amp;amp; full time development&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The future for Grafana looks very bright. I am, since last week, working on it full time. I currently have no sponsor
or income besides my company (Coding Instinct AB) savings. So any company that wants to sponsor development, can get
their logo on the start page, mentions in release notes and emails. Please email me at &lt;a href="mailto:contact@grafana.org"&gt;torkel@grafana.org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another avenue that I am going to explore, if sponsoring does not pan out,
is working on a paid premium version and a hosted version. There is so much more that can
be done with Grafana in turns of future features, improvements and polish. There is also a a lot of time consuming
maintainaince (library upgrades), support and documentation that needs to be done. So full time development is
really needed. The question is how to finance it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="meetups,-conferences-&amp;amp;-company-talks/coaching"&gt;Meetups, Conferences &amp;amp; Company talks/coaching&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want me to come talk about Grafana, application metrics, build measure learn or Graphite.
Please email me at &lt;a href="mailto:contact@grafana.org"&gt;torkel@grafana.org&lt;/a&gt;. I live in Stockholm Sweden so
travel could be an issue, but I am flexible and avaiable :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cheers &amp;amp; keep on graphing!&lt;br&gt;
Torkel&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Grafana 1.6.0 released.</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://grafana.org/blog/2014/06/16/Grafana-1-6-0-Released.html"/>
    <id>http://grafana.org/blog/2014/06/16/Grafana-1-6-0-Released.html</id>
    <published>2014-06-16T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2014-06-16T18:22:32+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Torkel Ödegaard</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;New release today! v1.6.0 is now available for &lt;a href="/download"&gt;download&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a pretty big release with a many of small improvements and new features.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="opentsdb"&gt;OpenTSDB&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This release marks the first release with initial support for &lt;a href="http://opentsdb.net/"&gt;OpenTSDB&lt;/a&gt;
as a metrics datasource. Checkout the docs article for &lt;a href="/docs/features/opentsdb"&gt;how to configure opentsdb&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/assets/img/opentsdb/editor_v1.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="dashboard-editing-improvements"&gt;Dashboard editing improvements&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Adding, moving and changing row settings as well as adding panels is much improved.
The row edit icon on the right of the row has been changed into a menu with quick options
to move the panel up/down, set height, add panel and delete.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/assets/img/animated_gifs/row_edit_menu.gif" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="influxdb-query-editor-improvements"&gt;InfluxDB query editor improvements&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The query editor is enhanced and more space efficient.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/assets/img/animated_gifs/influxdb_func_editor.gif" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="influxdb-group-by"&gt;InfluxDB group by&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can now group a single influxdb series into many grafana series by clicking
on the plus icon and specifying a column to group by.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/assets/img/influxdb/influxdb_query_editor_group_by.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="influxdb-filtering/templated-queries"&gt;InfluxDB filtering/templated queries&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can now use the filtering feature (templated queries) with InfluxDB.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/assets/img/influxdb/templated_query.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="changes"&gt;Changes&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The graphite panel is now renamed to simply &lt;code class="prettyprint"&gt;graph&lt;/code&gt;. Old dashboards will still work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are many more changes and improvements, checkout the complete changelog on the
&lt;a href="/download"&gt;download&lt;/a&gt; page.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Video from Monitorama Grafana workshop and project status update</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://grafana.org/blog/2014/05/25/monitorama-video-and-update.html"/>
    <id>http://grafana.org/blog/2014/05/25/monitorama-video-and-update.html</id>
    <published>2014-05-25T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2014-06-01T17:02:36+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Torkel Ödegaard</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;iframe src="//player.vimeo.com/video/95316672?portrait=0" width="500" height="281" frameborder="0" webkitallowfullscreen mozallowfullscreen allowfullscreen style="padding-bottom: 10px"&gt;

&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Monitorama conference was a blast. If you did not get a chance to attend you can still checkout all the presentations
at &lt;a href="http://vimeo.com/monitorama"&gt;vimeo.com/monitorama&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the end of the presentation I talk a little bit about the future for Grafana. Especially noteworthy is the fact that
I will be working full time on Grafana and related things by the end of July.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I apologize for the slow progress on pull requests. The last 3-4 weeks has been busy with preparing conferences (and the US trip) as well
as recovering from a pretty intense (no free/relax time) period as all work on Grafana is done in evenings and weekends. That should change in
the coming weeks but especially after July!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are currently &amp;gt;150 open github issues. Almost all are for small/large enhancements and general improvement ideas. So there is so much fun stuff that can really make a big difference
in how we consume, visualize, share metrics. I am incredibly excited about the coming months.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are interested in Sponsoring Grafana development or collaborate in anyway please &lt;a href="mailto:torkel@grafana.org"&gt;let me know&lt;/a&gt;. After summer I will also be available for meetups, workshops and
Graphite coaching.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;PS. &lt;a href="http://influxdb.org"&gt;InfluxDB&lt;/a&gt; just launched a hosting service for InfluxDB and Grafana.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Grafana 1.5.4 released.</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://grafana.org/blog/2014/05/13/Grafana-1-5-4-released.html"/>
    <id>http://grafana.org/blog/2014/05/13/Grafana-1-5-4-released.html</id>
    <published>2014-05-13T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2014-06-01T17:02:36+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Torkel Ödegaard</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;New release today! v1.5.4 is now available for &lt;a href="/download"&gt;download&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some small new features and enhancements. Check the download page for a complete changelog.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One notable change is the unsaved changes tracking. You now get a warning when moving to another dashboard without
having saved your changes, or when you close tab / window.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/assets/img/blog/unsaved_changes_dialog.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The progress for bigger new features and improvements has been slow. There are a number of pull requests that are wating for review. Preparation
for Monitorama PDX conference talk and the week in US has been the main reason. I have another talk at a conference next week as well which
will limit Grafana time. I currently only have evenings and weekends to spend working on Grafana.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After June that will all change. From July and onwards I will be working on Grafana and Grafana related things full time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you haven&amp;rsquo;t noticed there is now a &lt;a href="http://play.grafana.org"&gt;live playground and demo site&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Monitorama PDX.</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://grafana.org/blog/2014/05/01/monitorama.html"/>
    <id>http://grafana.org/blog/2014/05/01/monitorama.html</id>
    <published>2014-05-01T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2014-06-01T17:02:36+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Torkel Ödegaard</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;On Saturday I am flying to Portland for what I am hoping to be a great conference, &lt;a href="http://monitorama.com/"&gt;Monitorama PDX&lt;/a&gt;. The last day of the
conference is full hackathon day with workshops and lightning talks. I will present a workshop on Grafana that I hope to fill with some project
background, demos, tips and ticks, interesting ways to use graphite, questions and answers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was added kind of late to the speaker line up so it has
been a busy week trying to get a publicly accessable demo and playground ready so everyone can try and play with Grafana.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After Portland I will fly to San Fransciso for a short 2 day visit. Incredibly excited for the coming week!.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I will bring many Grafana stickers and a few tshirts so be sure to seek my out or attend the workshop!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class="row"&gt;
    &lt;img src="/assets/img/blog/stickers.jpg" class="medium-4 columns" /&gt;
    &lt;img src="/assets/img/blog/tshirt.jpg" class="medium-8 columns" /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title/>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://grafana.org/blog/2014/04/17/new-grafana-org-site.html"/>
    <id>http://grafana.org/blog/2014/04/17/new-grafana-org-site.html</id>
    <published>2014-04-17T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2014-08-05T13:44:35+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Torkel Ödegaard</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The new website is now live! Time to finish up the v1.6 release!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
</feed>
