<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Grafana Blog</title>
  <subtitle>Blog posts on Grafana, Metrics, Graphite, Monitoring, Build measure learn</subtitle>
  <id>http://grafana.org/blog</id>
  <link href="http://grafana.org/blog"/>
  <link href="http://grafana.org/feed.xml" rel="self"/>
  <updated>2014-09-11T00:00:00Z</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Grafana</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <title>Grafana 1.8.0-rc1 Released!</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://grafana.org/blog/2014/09/11/grafana-1-8-0-rc1-released.html"/>
    <id>http://grafana.org/blog/2014/09/11/grafana-1-8-0-rc1-released.html</id>
    <published>2014-09-11T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2014-09-12T16:24:17+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Torkel Ödegaard</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;New release today! v1.8.0-rc1 is now available for &lt;a href="/download"&gt;download&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is probably the biggest release since the first version was released. So many new features, enhancements and general UI improvements
that this will likely be a very long blog post. &lt;a href="http://play.grafana.org"&gt;play.grafana.org&lt;/a&gt; is updated to
run 1.8.0-rc1, now with InfluxDB demo dashboards. There is also a &lt;a href="http://play.grafana.org/#/dashboard/db/new-features-in-v18"&gt;New features in v1.8&lt;/a&gt;
dashboard that highlights some of the new features.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="release-highlights"&gt;Release highlights&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h4 id="1)-mixed-graph-styling"&gt;1) Mixed graph styling&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can override any display setting for a specific series using the series name or a regex pattern. Mix bars with lines, or disable
stacking for the right y-axis or any combination you can think of!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/assets/img/blog/mixed_styles.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You find these options under display styles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/assets/img/blog/series_override_options.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id="2)-improved-templating-system"&gt;2) Improved templating system&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The templating system has been completly rewritten. This feature was previously called filtering. From 1.8 it is renamed to templating.
Templating allows you to create variables that you can use in metric queries, annotation queries and panel titles to create generic reusable
dashboards. The new templating system uses a &lt;code class="prettyprint"&gt;$variable&lt;/code&gt; syntax, but the old &lt;code class="prettyprint"&gt;[[variable]]&lt;/code&gt; still works.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;New templating editor&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/assets/img/blog/template_variable_list.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The new templating system now has full support for InfluxDB. You can extract parts of a metric name using a regex.
You also have full control over how the &amp;ldquo;All&amp;rdquo; option should be formated so that it works for different
data sources.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/assets/img/blog/template_editor_influxdb.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;InfluxDB users should use &lt;code class="prettyprint"&gt;regex wildcard&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code class="prettyprint"&gt;regex values&lt;/code&gt; for the &lt;code class="prettyprint"&gt;All&lt;/code&gt; option format.
Graphite users should use &lt;code class="prettyprint"&gt;glob&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code class="prettyprint"&gt;wildcard&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Variables in Graphite function parameters&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
You can now use template variables for function parameters. There is a special template variable type called &lt;code class="prettyprint"&gt;interval&lt;/code&gt; that includes
and auto value, where the interval is calculated based on the time range.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/assets/img/blog/graphite_func_variables.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/assets/img/docs/template_variable_interval.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Template variable selection&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
When selecting template variables you now get a text box and and auto complete dropdown. Useful when you have many posible values for
a variable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id="3)-ui-improvements"&gt;3) UI Improvements&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;No more modals&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
All editors are now shown in an edit pane under the menu. This feels much more natural and faster.
All editors have also been polished and generally look a little better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/assets/img/blog/new_editor_look.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Improved search &amp;amp; tags&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
The search results view has been given a makeover, now with colored tags.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/assets/img/blog/new_search_look.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can navigate the search results with your up/down keys. The first
result is always highlighted. Hit enter to open the dashboard. You can add tags in the dashboard
settings edit pane. You can hit the tab key, to focus the tags link, hit enter again to get
an overview of all tags, click on the tag to filter by the tag.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id="4)-improved-graphite-query-editor"&gt;4) Improved Graphite Query editor&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many graphite functions can take other series as arguments. This was something the old
query editor could not handle. But the new improved query editor allows you to use
other queries as function arguments. To refer to another query you use a letter, like &lt;code class="prettyprint"&gt;#A&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/assets/img/blog/graphite_complex_query1.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Or a shorter version of the same thing:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/assets/img/blog/graphite_complex_query2.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is very powerful as it allows you to reuse queries in complex expressions. For example
plot a total and a percentage. If a query is only to be used in another query and not drawn
simply hide it using the eye.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id="5)-influxdb-query-editor-enhancements"&gt;5) InfluxDB Query Editor enhancements&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The query editor for InfluxDB has been upgraded. There are now two rows for each query, so more space
for potentially long series names. There is now an option to add &lt;code class="prettyprint"&gt;fill(null)&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code class="prettyprint"&gt;fill(0)&lt;/code&gt;. These options
are very important to understand and use because they solve some important scenarios that has troubled many
InfluxDB users.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/assets/img/blog/influxdb_new_query_editor.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A setting that is very important in combination with &lt;code class="prettyprint"&gt;fill(0)&lt;/code&gt; is the new group by time option below your
queries. This option allows you to set a fixed group by time for all queries, but more importantly it allows
you to set a lower limit for the auto group by time. When using &lt;code class="prettyprint"&gt;fill(0)&lt;/code&gt; you do not want to insert
zeros between real measurements, so you group by time must never be below the rate of writes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A low limit for the auto group by time is set using &lt;code class="prettyprint"&gt;&amp;gt;10s&lt;/code&gt; syntax. This feature together with &lt;code class="prettyprint"&gt;fill(0)&lt;/code&gt; is important when stacking multiple
series to ensure that every series have values for every time point.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id="6)-influxdb-breaking-changes"&gt;6) InfluxDB breaking changes&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am sorry to say that there are some breaking changes in 1.8 for InfluxDB users. All queries that used
a where clause or raw queries needs to be updated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Raw Queries&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="highlight sql"&gt;&lt;span class="k"&gt;select&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;mean&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;value&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="k"&gt;from&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="nv"&gt;&amp;quot;app.status&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="k"&gt;where&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="err"&gt;$&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;timeFilter&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="k"&gt;group&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="k"&gt;by&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;time&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="err"&gt;$&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;interval&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;fill&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="mi"&gt;0&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="k"&gt;order&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="k"&gt;asc&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Raw queries are now required to include &lt;code class="prettyprint"&gt;$timeFilter&lt;/code&gt; variable for time range, and zoom to work. Before
Grafana tried to parse and inject the time range filter in the right place, but this was fragile and could
lead to double time where conditions if there already was one in the query. Raw queries can now use,
optionally, a &lt;code class="prettyprint"&gt;$interval&lt;/code&gt; variable which will be replaced with the auto group by time interval.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Where condition&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 1.7.0 you could add a single where condition, using a dropdown to select column, operation, and value.
This was overly complicated, and is now replaced with a single where condition text box where you
can enter any number of where conditions. If you open a graph in edit mode the editor will try to
patch the query (using the old model) to build the where condition for you. But you will have to
enter edit mode for this &amp;ldquo;patch&amp;rdquo; process to work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id="6)-misc-improvements"&gt;6) Misc improvements&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Url state for panel edit and fullscreen mode, copy url and you will be taken to edit or fullscreen for that panel&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;from and to date range filters can be passed via url, see &lt;a href="https://github.com/grafana/grafana/issues/787"&gt;Issue #787&lt;/a&gt;
for more details&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A full share feature, where you can share a panel or dashboard with the current time range did not
make it for this release. But will be coming.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id="7)-documentation"&gt;7) Documentation&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The documentation for the new features and changes has yet to be done. That will be the focus for next
week. In the mean time, this blog post and the demo dashboards on &lt;a href="http://play.grafana.org"&gt;play.grafana.org&lt;/a&gt;
will have to suffice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id="8)-download"&gt;8) Download&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even though I have two project sponsors, it is not enough
for me to work full time and long term on Grafana. So please &lt;a href="/donate"&gt;pay what you think it is worth&lt;/a&gt;, and head to the &lt;a href="/download"&gt;download&lt;/a&gt; page
for download links and a complete changelog.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="nyc-grafana-+-influxdb-meetup-on-oct-8th"&gt;NYC Grafana + InfluxDB Meetup on Oct 8th&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I will be flying to New York on Oct 5th and will stay for two weeks. My project sponsor
&lt;a href="http://www.squarespace.com/"&gt;Squarespace&lt;/a&gt; will be hosting a meetup on Oct 8th where I
and Paul Dix from InfluxDB will be speaking. &lt;a href="http://www.meetup.com/Monitoring-NYC/events/205947512/"&gt;Sign up&lt;/a&gt;
for the meetup!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="meetups,-conferences-&amp;amp;-company-talks/coaching"&gt;Meetups, Conferences &amp;amp; Company talks/coaching&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want me to come talk about Grafana, application metrics, build measure learn or Graphite.
Please email me at &lt;a href="mailto:contact@grafana.org"&gt;torkel@grafana.org&lt;/a&gt;. I live in Stockholm Sweden so
travel could be an issue, but I am flexible and available :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cheers &amp;amp; keep on graphing!&lt;br&gt;
Torkel&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Big thanks to my sponsors&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.squarespace.com"&gt;Sponsored by Squarespace&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.dreamhost.com"&gt;Sponsored by Dreamhost&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Grafana 1.7.0-rc1 Released!</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://grafana.org/blog/2014/08/05/grafana-1-7-0-rc1-released.html"/>
    <id>http://grafana.org/blog/2014/08/05/grafana-1-7-0-rc1-released.html</id>
    <published>2014-08-05T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2014-08-05T15:55:34+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Torkel Ödegaard</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;New release today! v1.7.0-rc1 is now available for &lt;a href="/download"&gt;download&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a big release with a many new features and improvements. There are also a large number
of architectural changes (hence the release candidate status).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="release-highlights"&gt;Release highlights&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;InfluxDB can now be used as dashboard storage&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;InfluxDB can be used as a data source for annotations&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;InfluxDB series aliasing improvements (alias patterns)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Elasticsearch can be used as an annotation data source&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;New &lt;strong&gt;graph legend&lt;/strong&gt; options: &lt;em&gt;Align as table&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Right side&lt;/em&gt;.
Align as table will list series in vertical column, legend values will also align. Right side will place
the legend to the right side of the graph.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/assets/img/docs/graph_legend_right_table.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="documentation"&gt;Documentation&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The documentation has also seen an overhaul with many improvements and additions. A new &lt;a href="/docs/features/intro"&gt;Getting started&lt;/a&gt; guide
and a new &lt;a href="/docs/troubleshooting"&gt;Troubleshooting&lt;/a&gt; guide for example.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="fixes-and-small-additions"&gt;Fixes and small additions&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are also a number of small improvements and fixes in this release. It also has a number of architectural improvements
that will make future features and additions easier to implement and manage. Check the changelog on the &lt;a href="/download"&gt;download page&lt;/a&gt;
for a complete list.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="grafana-&amp;amp;-full-time-development"&gt;Grafana &amp;amp; full time development&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The future for Grafana looks very bright. I am, since last week, working on it full time. I currently have no sponsor
or income besides my company (Coding Instinct AB) savings. So any company that wants to sponsor development, can get
their logo on the start page, mentions in release notes and emails. Please email me at &lt;a href="mailto:contact@grafana.org"&gt;torkel@grafana.org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another avenue that I am going to explore, if sponsoring does not pan out,
is working on a paid premium version and a hosted version. There is so much more that can
be done with Grafana in turns of future features, improvements and polish. There is also a a lot of time consuming
maintainaince (library upgrades), support and documentation that needs to be done. So full time development is
really needed. The question is how to finance it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="meetups,-conferences-&amp;amp;-company-talks/coaching"&gt;Meetups, Conferences &amp;amp; Company talks/coaching&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want me to come talk about Grafana, application metrics, build measure learn or Graphite.
Please email me at &lt;a href="mailto:contact@grafana.org"&gt;torkel@grafana.org&lt;/a&gt;. I live in Stockholm Sweden so
travel could be an issue, but I am flexible and available :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cheers &amp;amp; keep on graphing!&lt;br&gt;
Torkel&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Grafana 1.6.0 released.</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://grafana.org/blog/2014/06/16/Grafana-1-6-0-Released.html"/>
    <id>http://grafana.org/blog/2014/06/16/Grafana-1-6-0-Released.html</id>
    <published>2014-06-16T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2014-06-16T18:22:32+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Torkel Ödegaard</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;New release today! v1.6.0 is now available for &lt;a href="/download"&gt;download&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a pretty big release with a many of small improvements and new features.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="opentsdb"&gt;OpenTSDB&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This release marks the first release with initial support for &lt;a href="http://opentsdb.net/"&gt;OpenTSDB&lt;/a&gt;
as a metrics datasource. Checkout the docs article for &lt;a href="/docs/features/opentsdb"&gt;how to configure opentsdb&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/assets/img/opentsdb/editor_v1.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="dashboard-editing-improvements"&gt;Dashboard editing improvements&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Adding, moving and changing row settings as well as adding panels is much improved.
The row edit icon on the right of the row has been changed into a menu with quick options
to move the panel up/down, set height, add panel and delete.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/assets/img/animated_gifs/row_edit_menu.gif" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="influxdb-query-editor-improvements"&gt;InfluxDB query editor improvements&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The query editor is enhanced and more space efficient.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/assets/img/animated_gifs/influxdb_func_editor.gif" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="influxdb-group-by"&gt;InfluxDB group by&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can now group a single influxdb series into many grafana series by clicking
on the plus icon and specifying a column to group by.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/assets/img/influxdb/influxdb_query_editor_group_by.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="influxdb-filtering/templated-queries"&gt;InfluxDB filtering/templated queries&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can now use the filtering feature (templated queries) with InfluxDB.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/assets/img/influxdb/templated_query.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="changes"&gt;Changes&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The graphite panel is now renamed to simply &lt;code class="prettyprint"&gt;graph&lt;/code&gt;. Old dashboards will still work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are many more changes and improvements, checkout the complete changelog on the
&lt;a href="/download"&gt;download&lt;/a&gt; page.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Video from Monitorama Grafana workshop and project status update</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://grafana.org/blog/2014/05/25/monitorama-video-and-update.html"/>
    <id>http://grafana.org/blog/2014/05/25/monitorama-video-and-update.html</id>
    <published>2014-05-25T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2014-06-01T17:02:36+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Torkel Ödegaard</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;iframe src="//player.vimeo.com/video/95316672?portrait=0" width="500" height="281" frameborder="0" webkitallowfullscreen mozallowfullscreen allowfullscreen style="padding-bottom: 10px"&gt;

&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Monitorama conference was a blast. If you did not get a chance to attend you can still checkout all the presentations
at &lt;a href="http://vimeo.com/monitorama"&gt;vimeo.com/monitorama&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the end of the presentation I talk a little bit about the future for Grafana. Especially noteworthy is the fact that
I will be working full time on Grafana and related things by the end of July.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I apologize for the slow progress on pull requests. The last 3-4 weeks has been busy with preparing conferences (and the US trip) as well
as recovering from a pretty intense (no free/relax time) period as all work on Grafana is done in evenings and weekends. That should change in
the coming weeks but especially after July!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are currently &amp;gt;150 open github issues. Almost all are for small/large enhancements and general improvement ideas. So there is so much fun stuff that can really make a big difference
in how we consume, visualize, share metrics. I am incredibly excited about the coming months.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are interested in Sponsoring Grafana development or collaborate in anyway please &lt;a href="mailto:torkel@grafana.org"&gt;let me know&lt;/a&gt;. After summer I will also be available for meetups, workshops and
Graphite coaching.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;PS. &lt;a href="http://influxdb.org"&gt;InfluxDB&lt;/a&gt; just launched a hosting service for InfluxDB and Grafana.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Grafana 1.5.4 released.</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://grafana.org/blog/2014/05/13/Grafana-1-5-4-released.html"/>
    <id>http://grafana.org/blog/2014/05/13/Grafana-1-5-4-released.html</id>
    <published>2014-05-13T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2014-06-01T17:02:36+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Torkel Ödegaard</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;New release today! v1.5.4 is now available for &lt;a href="/download"&gt;download&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some small new features and enhancements. Check the download page for a complete changelog.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One notable change is the unsaved changes tracking. You now get a warning when moving to another dashboard without
having saved your changes, or when you close tab / window.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/assets/img/blog/unsaved_changes_dialog.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The progress for bigger new features and improvements has been slow. There are a number of pull requests that are wating for review. Preparation
for Monitorama PDX conference talk and the week in US has been the main reason. I have another talk at a conference next week as well which
will limit Grafana time. I currently only have evenings and weekends to spend working on Grafana.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After June that will all change. From July and onwards I will be working on Grafana and Grafana related things full time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you haven&amp;rsquo;t noticed there is now a &lt;a href="http://play.grafana.org"&gt;live playground and demo site&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Monitorama PDX.</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://grafana.org/blog/2014/05/01/monitorama.html"/>
    <id>http://grafana.org/blog/2014/05/01/monitorama.html</id>
    <published>2014-05-01T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2014-06-01T17:02:36+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Torkel Ödegaard</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;On Saturday I am flying to Portland for what I am hoping to be a great conference, &lt;a href="http://monitorama.com/"&gt;Monitorama PDX&lt;/a&gt;. The last day of the
conference is full hackathon day with workshops and lightning talks. I will present a workshop on Grafana that I hope to fill with some project
background, demos, tips and ticks, interesting ways to use graphite, questions and answers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was added kind of late to the speaker line up so it has
been a busy week trying to get a publicly accessable demo and playground ready so everyone can try and play with Grafana.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After Portland I will fly to San Fransciso for a short 2 day visit. Incredibly excited for the coming week!.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I will bring many Grafana stickers and a few tshirts so be sure to seek my out or attend the workshop!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class="row"&gt;
    &lt;img src="/assets/img/blog/stickers.jpg" class="medium-4 columns" /&gt;
    &lt;img src="/assets/img/blog/tshirt.jpg" class="medium-8 columns" /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
</feed>
